Guide to the Charles K. Field Cheerio Records M1533
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles K. Field Cheerio records
1927-1943
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Cheerio (Radio program)
Field, Charles K. (Charles Kellogg), 1873-1948
M1533
6 Linear Feet: 8 boxes, 1 flat box
Records documenting production of the popular 1930s radio program Cheerio, from the show's creator, Charles Kellogg Field.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Rare Books, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Related Materials
Stanford University Archives holds the Charles K. Field Collection (SC0575) http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5870397n
Hoover Institution holds Charles Kellogg Field typescript: Distinguished soldiers in World War I (YY155) http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5779r741
The Library of Congress holds appoximately fifteen recordings of the Cheerio program dating from 1935 to 1940.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains various files related to Cheerio's production from 1927 to 1943, including program synopses, scripts and cue sheets, and annotated sheet music. It is very likely that this material was separated from Field's personal papers, which are held by Stanford University Archives.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Kellogg Field (1873-1948) was a member of Stanford University's pioneer class, graduating in 1895 with an A.B. in English. Field wrote Four-leaved Clover: Being Stanford Rhymes in 1896 under the pen name Carolus Ager and wrote Stanford Stories in 1900 with author Will Irwin. He was a member of the Bohemian Club and literary circles during the early part of the century, and wrote several Bohemian Grove plays between 1902 and 1918. In 1908 he became associate editor of the Sunset Magazine, and worked for that magazine for several years. Field entered broadcasting in his sixties with the popular radio program Cheerio.
Cheerio was first broadcast from San Francisco's KGO in 1925, but became nationally known upon his move to New York City in 1927. The program aired weekday mornings on NBC's Blue Network to an audience primarily of housewives, and featured his poetry and inspirational lectures accompanied by singing, organ, and orchestral music. Cheerio included various segments focusing on music, drama and children's health advice, and Field (performing as Cheerio) was also featured on related programs sponsored by ARCO. Despite retaining his anonymity (no press pictures were permitted, and his fee was donated to charity), he wrote the autobiographical Story of Cheerio in 1936, and also authored Cheerio’s Book of Days; Comfort, Cheer and Encouragement for Every Day in the Year in 1940.
Radio -- History; Cheerio (Radio program); Field, Charles K. (Charles Kellogg), 1873-1948
- Series 1. Cheerio - Child Health - Program/Cues
  - 1927 (Box 1, Folders 1-2)
  - 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1929 (Box 1, Folders 4-5)
  - 1930 (Box 2, Folders 1-4)
  - 1931 (Box 3, Folders 1-5)
  - 1932 (Box 4, Folders 1-2)
- Series 2. Cheerio - Program/Cues
  - 1933 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 10th Anniversary, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1938 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - 1939 (Box 5, Folders 5-6)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series 3. Cheerio's Musical Mosaics
  - 1933 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Series 4. Cheerio - Dramatics
  - 1927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1928 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1929-1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series 5. The Toastmaster - ARCO Birthday Party Program
  - 1930 (Box 7, Folders 1-5)
  - 1931 (Box 8, Folders 1-3)
- Series 6. The Chairman - ARCO Dramatic Musicale Program
  - 1931 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Series 7. Cheerio Program Background Sheet Music
  - Sunday Night Cheerio Program Background Sheet Music (Box 9, Folders 1-2)
  - Cheerio Morning Program Musical Mosaics Sheet Music (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Series 8. Cheerio Sunday Night Program Schedule
  - Scrapbook, 1937-1940 (Box 9, Folder 4)